Honor made him a man. Courage made him a hero. History made him a legend.
Rob Roy is a adventure, history, drama film directed by Michael Caton-Jones.
In the highlands of Scotland in the 1700s, Rob Roy tries to lead his small town to a better
future, by borrowing money from the local nobility to buy cattle to herd to market.
When the money is stolen, Rob is forced into a Robin Hood
lifestyle to defend his family and honour.
Robert Roy MacGregor, played by Liam Neeson.
Mary MacGregor, played by Jessica Lange.
John Graham, played by John Hurt.
Archibald Cunningham, played by Tim Roth.
Alan MacDonald, played by Eric Stoltz.
Killearn, played by Brian Cox.
Rob Roy is a 1995 historical biographical  drama
film directed by Michael Caton-Jones.
It stars Liam Neeson as Rob Roy MacGregor, an 18th-century Scottish highlander who becomes
engaged in a dispute with a nobleman in the Scottish Highlands, played by John Hurt.
Tim Roth won the BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Supporting Role and was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Supporting Actor for his portrayal of Archibald Cunningham, one of Rob Roy's chief antagonists.
Jessica Lange portrays Roy's wife, and Eric Stoltz, Brian
Cox, and Jason Flemyng play supporting parts.
The film is dedicated to two Scotsmen: film director Alexander
MacKendrick and football player and manager Jock Stein.
The film explores themes of scotland, affectation,
biography, 18th century, highlands.
The tone is uplifting and dark and emotional.